<story-context id="bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>1</epicId>
    <storyId>12</storyId>
    <title>Initial Marketing Website (Cloudflare Workers)</title>
    <status>ready-for-dev</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-10-29</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>docs/stories/1-12-initial-marketing-website.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>project maintainer</asA>
    <iWant>an initial marketing website hosted on Cloudflare Workers</iWant>
    <soThat>early adopters can learn about Tamma and sign up for updates before the full documentation site launches</soThat>
    <tasks>Task 1: Design and content creation (AC: 1, 2, 6)
  Subtask 1.1: Write homepage copy (tagline, key features, CTA)
  Subtask 1.2: Design wireframe/mockup (responsive layout)
  Subtask 1.3: Create logo and brand assets (or use placeholder)
  Subtask 1.4: Write "Why Tamma?" section explaining self-maintenance goal
  Subtask 1.5: Create roadmap visualization (timeline or milestone cards)

Task 2: Cloudflare Workers setup (AC: 1)
  Subtask 2.1: Create Cloudflare account and set up Workers project
  Subtask 2.2: Configure custom domain (DNS, SSL certificate)
  Subtask 2.3: Set up Cloudflare Pages for static site hosting (alternative to Workers)
  Subtask 2.4: Configure caching and CDN settings

Task 3: Email signup implementation (AC: 3)
  Subtask 3.1: Create HTML form with email input and submit button
  Subtask 3.2: Implement serverless function to handle form submission
  Subtask 3.3: Store emails in Cloudflare KV or integrate with Mailchimp/ConvertKit
  Subtask 3.4: Send confirmation email to subscribers (optional)
  Subtask 3.5: Add email validation and anti-spam protection (reCAPTCHA or hCaptcha)

Task 4: Content pages (AC: 4, 9)
  Subtask 4.1: Create GitHub repo link with clear CTA ("Get Early Access")
  Subtask 4.2: Write privacy policy (template from privacy policy generator)
  Subtask 4.3: Write terms of service (template)
  Subtask 4.4: Add footer with links to policies and GitHub

Task 5: Responsive design and performance (AC: 7)
  Subtask 5.1: Implement responsive CSS (mobile-first approach)
  Subtask 5.2: Test on mobile devices (iOS Safari, Android Chrome)
  Subtask 5.3: Optimize images (WebP format, lazy loading)
  Subtask 5.4: Minimize CSS/JS (inline critical CSS, defer non-critical)
  Subtask 5.5: Test load time with Lighthouse (<1 second target)

Task 6: SEO and social sharing (AC: 8)
  Subtask 6.1: Add meta tags (title, description, keywords)
  Subtask 6.2: Add Open Graph tags for Facebook/LinkedIn sharing
  Subtask 6.3: Add Twitter Card tags for Twitter sharing
  Subtask 6.4: Add structured data (JSON-LD for rich snippets)
  Subtask 6.5: Create sitemap.xml and robots.txt

Task 7: Analytics and monitoring (AC: 10)
  Subtask 7.1: Integrate Cloudflare Web Analytics (privacy-respecting, no cookies)
  Subtask 7.2: Set up monitoring for email signup success rate
  Subtask 7.3: Add error tracking (Cloudflare Workers logging)

Task 8: Testing and deployment (AC: 1-10)
  Subtask 8.1: Test all links and email signup flow
  Subtask 8.2: Test responsive design on multiple devices
  Subtask 8.3: Deploy to Cloudflare Workers/Pages
  Subtask 8.4: Test production site (DNS, SSL, load time)
  Subtask 8.5: Announce site on GitHub README and social media</tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>1. Static website hosted on Cloudflare Workers with custom domain (tamma.dev or similar)
2. Homepage includes: project name, tagline, key features overview, "Coming Soon" message
3. Email signup form for launch notifications (stores emails in Cloudflare KV or external service)
4. Link to GitHub repository for early access
5. Roadmap section showing Epic 1-5 timeline and MVP goals
6. "Why Tamma?" section explaining self-maintenance goal and multi-provider support
7. Responsive design (mobile, tablet, desktop) with fast load times (<1 second)
8. SEO optimization (meta tags, Open Graph, Twitter Cards)
9. Privacy policy and terms of service pages (basic)
10. Analytics integration (privacy-respecting: Cloudflare Web Analytics or Plausible)</acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Goals & Background Context</section>
        <snippet>Tamma's goal is to create an autonomous development platform that maintains itself, with 70%+ completion rate without human intervention.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/architecture.md</path>
        <title>Architecture Overview</title>
        <section>System Design</section>
        <snippet>Hybrid orchestrator/worker architecture with event sourcing foundation for deterministic replay and audit trails.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/epics.md</path>
        <title>Epic Breakdown</title>
        <section>Roadmap Timeline</section>
        <snippet>Epic 1-5 covering Foundation, Autonomous Workflow, Intelligence, Event Sourcing, and Production Readiness across 10-week development cycle.</snippet>
      </doc>
      <doc>
        <path>docs/tech-spec-epic-1.md</path>
        <title>Epic 1 Technical Specification</title>
        <section>Foundation Requirements</section>
        <snippet>Multi-provider AI abstraction, Git platform integration, and hybrid deployment modes with comprehensive configuration management.</snippet>
      </doc>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <!-- No existing code artifacts found - this is a foundational marketing story -->
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <ecosystem name="web">
        <packages>
          <package name="cloudflare-workers" version="latest" />
          <package name="cloudflare-kv" version="latest" />
          <package name="cloudflare-pages" version="latest" />
          <package name="cloudflare-analytics" version="latest" />
        </packages>
      </ecosystem>
      <ecosystem name="email">
        <packages>
          <package name="mailchimp-api" version="latest" optional="true" />
          <package name="convertkit-api" version="latest" optional="true" />
        </packages>
      </ecosystem>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <constraint name="Hosting Platform">Must use Cloudflare Workers or Cloudflare Pages for global CDN and serverless capabilities</constraint>
    <constraint name="Performance">Target load times <1 second, Lighthouse score 95+ across all metrics</constraint>
    <constraint name="Responsive Design">Mobile-first approach with support for mobile, tablet, and desktop viewports</constraint>
    <constraint name="Privacy">Use privacy-respecting analytics (Cloudflare Web Analytics or Plausible), no cookies required</constraint>
    <constraint name="SEO">Complete meta tags, Open Graph, Twitter Cards, structured data, sitemap.xml</constraint>
    <constraint name="Email Collection">Simple email storage in Cloudflare KV or external service with validation and anti-spam</constraint>
    <constraint name="Brand Consistency">Follow established color scheme (blue #2563eb, green #10b981) and typography (Inter/sans-serif)</constraint>
    <constraint name="Content">Focus on self-maintenance value proposition and multi-provider flexibility as key differentiators</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <interfaces>
    <!-- No existing interfaces - this is a new marketing site implementation -->
  </interfaces>

  <tests>
    <standards>Manual testing approach for marketing site with focus on responsive design, load performance, SEO validation, and email signup functionality. Use Lighthouse for automated performance and accessibility testing.</standards>
    <locations>
      <location>Manual testing across devices (iOS Safari, Android Chrome, desktop browsers)</location>
      <location>Google Lighthouse for performance, accessibility, SEO scoring</location>
      <location>Cloudflare Workers testing environment for serverless functions</location>
    </locations>
    <ideas>
      <test idea="AC1">Verify Cloudflare Workers deployment with custom domain and SSL certificate</test>
      <test idea="AC2">Test homepage content display and "Coming Soon" messaging</test>
      <test idea="AC3">Test email signup form submission and storage in Cloudflare KV</test>
      <test idea="AC4">Verify GitHub repository link functionality and tracking</test>
      <test idea="AC5">Test roadmap section display and timeline visualization</test>
      <test idea="AC6">Verify "Why Tamma?" section content and self-maintenance messaging</test>
      <test idea="AC7">Test responsive design on mobile (320px+), tablet (768px+), desktop (1024px+)</test>
      <test idea="AC8">Validate SEO meta tags, Open Graph, Twitter Cards with social sharing tools</test>
      <test idea="AC9">Test privacy policy and terms of service page accessibility</test>
      <test idea="AC10">Verify Cloudflare Analytics integration and privacy compliance</test>
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>