<story-context id="bmad/bmm/workflows/4-implementation/story-context/template" v="1.0">
  <metadata>
    <epicId>3</epicId>
    <storyId>3</storyId>
    <title>Contamination Prevention System</title>
    <status>ready-for-dev</status>
    <generatedAt>2025-11-08T12:00:00.000Z</generatedAt>
    <generator>BMAD Story Context Workflow</generator>
    <sourceStoryPath>/home/meywd/tamma/test-platform/docs/stories/3-3-contamination-prevention-system.md</sourceStoryPath>
  </metadata>

  <story>
    <asA>benchmark maintainer</asA>
    <iWant>prevent AI models from training on our benchmark tasks through comprehensive contamination prevention measures</iWant>
    <soThat>benchmark results reflect genuine AI capability rather than memorization of training data</soThat>
    <tasks>Task 1: Private Test Suite Architecture
- Subtask 1.1: Design encrypted storage system for private test cases with AES-256 encryption
- Subtask 1.2: Implement role-based access control for test suite access with audit logging
- Subtask 1.3: Create public/private task separation with secure API endpoints
- Subtask 1.4: Build test suite versioning with secure distribution mechanisms
Task 2: Task Refreshment Engine
- Subtask 2.1: Develop semantic variation generation algorithms for task refreshment
- Subtask 2.2: Implement automated scheduling system for periodic task updates
- Subtask 2.3: Create difficulty preservation validation for refreshed tasks
- Subtask 2.4: Build task variation tracking and lineage management system
Task 3: Advanced Obfuscation System
- Subtask 3.1: Implement variable and function name randomization with semantic preservation
- Subtask 3.2: Create code structure randomization algorithms maintaining functionality
- Subtask 3.3: Develop comment and documentation obfuscation techniques
- Subtask 3.4: Build obfuscation validation system to ensure task integrity
Task 4: Training Data Monitoring
- Subtask 4.1: Implement GitHub repository scanning for task content leakage
- Subtask 4.2: Create training dataset analysis integration with major data providers
- Subtask 4.3: Build model output monitoring for task memorization detection
- Subtask 4.4: Develop real-time contamination alerting system
Task 5: Canary Task System
- Subtask 5.1: Design canary task generation with unique identifiers
- Subtask 5.2: Implement canary task embedding in benchmark workflows
- Subtask 5.3: Create canary result analysis for contamination detection
- Subtask 5.4: Build canary task rotation and replacement system
Task 6: Version Isolation Framework
- Subtask 6.1: Implement strict version separation with access controls
- Subtask 6.2: Create cross-version contamination prevention mechanisms
- Subtask 6.3: Build version access logging and monitoring
- Subtask 6.4: Develop version retirement and archival procedures
Task 7: Comprehensive Access Logging
- Subtask 7.1: Implement tamper-proof logging system for all task access
- Subtask 7.2: Create detailed access pattern analysis and anomaly detection
- Subtask 7.3: Build access audit trail with immutable storage
- Subtask 7.4: Develop access reporting and compliance documentation
Task 8: Automated Contamination Detection
- Subtask 8.1: Integrate AI models for contamination pattern recognition
- Subtask 8.2: Create contamination scoring algorithms with confidence metrics
- Subtask 8.3: Implement real-time alerting with escalation procedures
- Subtask 8.4: Build contamination response and mitigation workflows</tasks>
  </story>

  <acceptanceCriteria>1. Private Test Suite Separation: Implement strict separation between public task descriptions and private test cases with encrypted storage and access controls
2. Task Refreshment System: Automated periodic generation of task variations with semantic preservation to prevent pattern memorization
3. Task Obfuscation Techniques: Advanced obfuscation methods including variable renaming, structure randomization, and semantic preservation
4. Training Data Monitoring: Continuous monitoring of public repositories, training datasets, and model outputs for task content leakage
5. Canary Task Deployment: Special canary tasks embedded in benchmarks to detect contamination and model memorization patterns
6. Version Isolation Enforcement: Strict isolation between task versions with cross-contamination prevention and access logging
7. Comprehensive Access Logging: Complete audit trail of all task access, exposure, and distribution with tamper-proof logging
8. Automated Contamination Detection: AI-powered detection system with real-time alerts and contamination scoring</acceptanceCriteria>

  <artifacts>
    <docs>
      <artifact>
        <path>test-platform/docs/epics.md</path>
        <title>Epic 3: Test Bank Management</title>
        <section>Epic 3 Overview</section>
        <snippet>Epic 3 implements the comprehensive test bank management system that serves as the foundation for all AI benchmarking activities. This epic delivers the task repository with quality assurance mechanisms, contamination prevention systems, and an initial curated test bank covering various AI capabilities.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>test-platform/docs/tech-spec-epic-3.md</path>
        <title>Technical Specification for Epic 3</title>
        <section>Contamination Prevention System</section>
        <snippet>Contamination Prevention System - Data leakage detection and prevention. The system ensures test integrity, prevents data leakage between training and evaluation sets, and provides version control for benchmark tasks while maintaining scalability for thousands of test cases across multiple domains.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>test-platform/docs/PRD.md</path>
        <title>Product Requirements Document</title>
        <section>Test Bank Management</section>
        <snippet>Contamination Prevention: Private test suites with regular refreshment cycles. The platform introduces innovative approaches including contamination prevention to ensure results reflect genuine capability rather than memorization.</snippet>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>test-platform/docs/ARCHITECTURE.md</path>
        <title>Architecture Document</title>
        <section>Key Differentiators</section>
        <snippet>ONLY developer-focused benchmark with human percentile rankings and contamination prevention. The platform addresses the critical need for continuous, reliable AI model performance monitoring in the rapidly evolving landscape of AI code generation tools.</snippet>
      </artifact>
    </docs>
    <code>
      <artifact>
        <path>packages/shared/src/contracts/index.ts</path>
        <kind>interface</kind>
        <symbol>ILogger</symbol>
        <lines>6-11</lines>
        <reason>Existing logging interface that can be extended for contamination audit logging</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>packages/providers/src/types.test.ts</path>
        <kind>test</kind>
        <symbol>AI Provider Interfaces</symbol>
        <lines>1-302</lines>
        <reason>Existing test patterns and interface definitions that can inform contamination detection integration with AI providers</reason>
      </artifact>
      <artifact>
        <path>doc-review/db/schema.sql</path>
        <kind>schema</kind>
        <symbol>Database Schema</symbol>
        <lines>1-139</lines>
        <reason>Existing database schema patterns for user management, activity logging, and audit trails that can be adapted for contamination prevention</reason>
      </artifact>
    </code>
    <dependencies>
      <ecosystem>Node.js</ecosystem>
      <packages>
        <package name="typescript" version="~5.7.2" />
        <package name="vitest" version="^3.0.6" />
        <package name="esbuild" version="^0.24.2" />
        <package name="prettier" version="^3.4.2" />
        <package name="eslint" version="^9.18.0" />
      </packages>
      <frameworks>
        <framework name="PostgreSQL" purpose="Primary database for encrypted test storage and audit logging" />
        <framework name="TimescaleDB" purpose="Time-series data for contamination monitoring and trend analysis" />
        <framework name="Vitest" purpose="Testing framework with 10-20x faster performance than Jest" />
        <framework name="Pino" purpose="Structured logging for audit trails and contamination detection" />
      </frameworks>
    </dependencies>
  </artifacts>

  <constraints>
    <constraint>Zero-Knowledge Architecture: Private test cases encrypted with AES-256-GCM, decryption only during execution</constraint>
    <constraint>Semantic Variation Generation: Use LLM-powered task variation while preserving functional requirements and difficulty</constraint>
    <constraint>Multi-Layer Monitoring: GitHub API scanning, training dataset analysis, and model output monitoring for contamination detection</constraint>
    <constraint>Canary Task Strategy: Embed unique watermark tasks to detect memorization patterns across model evaluations</constraint>
    <constraint>Security Requirements: AES-256-GCM encryption, RBAC with just-in-time access, immutable audit logs, SOC2 Type II and ISO27001 compliance</constraint>
    <constraint>Performance Standards: Encryption &lt;50ms, variation generation &lt;5s, repository scanning &lt;24h for 10M repos, database queries &lt;50ms</constraint>
    <constraint>Testing Requirements: 100% test coverage on critical paths, TDD workflow, security penetration testing, performance validation</constraint>
  </constraints>

  <interfaces>
    <interface>
      <name>ContaminationPreventionSystem</name>
      <kind>class interface</kind>
      <signature>interface ContaminationPreventionSystem {
  encryptPrivateTests(taskId: string, testCases: TestCase[]): Promise&lt;EncryptedTests&gt;;
  decryptPrivateTests(encryptedTests: EncryptedTests, executionContext: ExecutionContext): Promise&lt;TestCase[]&gt;;
  generateTaskVariation(originalTask: Task, variationSeed: string): Promise&lt;TaskVariation&gt;;
  validateVariationIntegrity(original: Task, variation: TaskVariation): Promise&lt;VariationValidation&gt;;
  scanPublicRepositories(taskSignature: string): Promise&lt;ContaminationScan[]&gt;;
  analyzeTrainingDataExposure(taskPatterns: string[]): Promise&lt;ExposureReport&gt;;
  createCanaryTask(baseTask: Task, watermarkId: string): Promise&lt;CanaryTask&gt;;
  detectCanaryMemorization(evaluationResults: EvaluationResult[]): Promise&lt;MemorizationReport&gt;;
}</signature>
      <path>test-platform/docs/stories/3-3-contamination-prevention-system.md</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>ContaminationAnalyzer</name>
      <kind>class interface</kind>
      <signature>interface ContaminationAnalyzer {
  analyze(task: Task): Promise&lt;ContaminationAnalysis&gt;;
  getSimilarTasks(task: Task, threshold: number): Promise&lt;SimilarTask[]&gt;;
  checkTrainingDataOverlap(task: Task): Promise&lt;TrainingDataOverlap&gt;;
}</signature>
      <path>test-platform/docs/tech-spec-epic-3.md</path>
    </interface>
    <interface>
      <name>ObfuscationStrategy</name>
      <kind>class interface</kind>
      <signature>interface ObfuscationStrategy {
  randomizeIdentifiers(code: string, semanticMap: SemanticMap): Promise&lt;ObfuscatedCode&gt;;
  randomizeStructure(ast: ProgramAST, constraints: StructureConstraints): Promise&lt;ProgramAST&gt;;
  obfuscateDocumentation(docs: Documentation, preserveHints: string[]): Promise&lt;ObfuscatedDocs&gt;;
  transformControlFlow(ast: ProgramAST, preserveSemantics: boolean): Promise&lt;ProgramAST&gt;;
}</signature>
      <path>test-platform/docs/stories/3-3-contamination-prevention-system.md</path>
    </interface>
  </interfaces>

  <tests>
    <standards>Follow TDD workflow with Red-Green-Refactor cycle. Use Vitest 3.x for all testing. Target 100% test coverage on critical paths (encryption, access controls, contamination detection). Unit tests for individual components, integration tests for end-to-end contamination flows, security tests for penetration testing, and performance tests for scalability validation. Mock external APIs using MSW, use in-memory SQLite for database testing.</standards>
    <locations>Test files colocated with source using *.test.ts pattern. Integration tests in *.integration.test.ts files. Performance tests in separate perf/ directory. Security tests in security/ directory. Test utilities in test-utils/ directory.</locations>
    <ideas>
      <test idea="AC1">Test AES-256-GCM encryption/decryption with known-answer tests and key rotation scenarios</test>
      <test idea="AC2">Test semantic variation generation preserves difficulty and functional requirements across all 7 programming languages</test>
      <test idea="AC3">Test obfuscation techniques maintain code functionality while preventing pattern recognition</test>
      <test idea="AC4">Test GitHub API integration for repository scanning with rate limiting and error handling</test>
      <test idea="AC5">Test canary task watermark detection and memorization pattern recognition</test>
      <test idea="AC6">Test version isolation prevents cross-contamination with comprehensive access logging</test>
      <test idea="AC7">Test tamper-proof audit logging with immutable storage and anomaly detection</test>
      <test idea="AC8">Test AI-powered contamination detection with real-time alerting and escalation procedures</test>
    </ideas>
  </tests>
</story-context>